Guide to the Dept. of Consumer Economics and Housing records,1969-1997.
Dept. of Consumer Economics and Housing records,1969-1997.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Dept. of Consumer Economics and Housing records, 1969-1997.
23-23-2864
New York State College of Human Ecology.Dept. of Consumer Economics and Housing.
3.5 cubic ft.
Reading lists, annual reports, list of theses, department meeting minutes, master plan, photographs, and Five Year Review and correspondence
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Reading lists, annual reports, list of theses from 1926-1990, department meeting minutes, master plan, and Five Year Review and correspondence.
ORGANIZATIONAL HISTORY
In 1997, merged with Dept. of Human Service Studies to become Dept. of Policy Analysis and Management.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Reading lists, annual reports, list of theses from 1926-1990, department meeting minutes, master plan, and Five Year Review and correspondence.
SUBJECTS
Names:
New York State College of Human Ecology.; Cornell University--Faculty.
Subjects:
Consumer education--Study and teaching--New York (State)--Ithaca.; Consumers.; Housing--Study and teaching.
Form and Genre Terms:
Photographs.
INFORMATION FOR USERS
SERIES LIST
Series I. Correspondence
Box 2- Folder 55, Box 5- Folders 3-4, 6, 11-12
Series II. Curriculum
A. Course Outlines/ Reading Lists
Box 1- Folders 18-45, Box 2- Folders 46-54
B. Intro Economics Course
Box 5- Folders 9-10
C. Theses
Box 2- Folder 62, Box 6
Series III. Handbooks
A. Department
Box 4
B. Graduate
Box 5- Folder 17
Series IV. Minutes of Meetings
A. "The Committee" & Executive Committee
Box 5- Folder 5
B. Curriculum Committee
Box 5- Folders 7-8
C. Faculty Meetings
Box 1- Folders 10-17, Box 5- Folders 13-16
Series V. Publications
Box 5- Folder 18-19, Box7- Folders 1-5
Series VI. Reports/ Plans
A. Annual
Box 1- Folder 7-9, Box 3, Box 5- Folder 1-2
B. Five Year Plans
Box 1- Folder 2
C. Master Plans
Box 1- Folder 3
D. Reviews
Box 1, Folder 48, Box 4
E. Chair's Reports to the Dean
Box 1, Folder 46
F. Various other Reports
Box 1, Folder 49
Series VII. Subject Files
Box 1- Folders 1, 4-6, 47, 50 Box 2- Folders 56-61
Series VIII. Photographs
Box 7- Folder 7
CONTAINER LIST
- Series I. Correspondence
  - Correspondence, Memoranda, 1987-1994 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence, Memoranda, 1995-1997 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence between Chair (Keith Bryant) and Dean Firebaugh, 1988-1996 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Extension/Consumer Economics and Housing Memoranda, Correspondence, 1987-1992 (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - Extension/Consumer Economics and Housing Memoranda, Correspondence, 1993-1996 (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - Correspondence-Department, 1996-1997 (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence-Department, 1993-1995 (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence-Department, 1980-1991 (Box 8, Folder 3)
- Series II. Curriculum
  - A. Course Outlines/ Reading Lists
    - Reading Lists, 1973 (Box 1, Folder 18)
      Fall
    - Course Outlines, 1973 (Box 1, Folder 19)
    - Reading Lists/Outlines, 1974 (Box 1, Folder 20)
      Spring
    - Reading Lists/Outlines, 1974 (Box 1, Folder 21)
    - Reading Lists/Outlines, 1975 (Box 1, Folder 22)
    - Reading Lists/Outlines, 1975 (Box 1, Folder 23)
    - Reading Lists/Outlines, 1976 (Box 1, Folder 24)
    - Reading Lists/Outlines, 1976 (Box 1, Folder 25)
    - Reading Lists/Outlines, 1977 (Box 1, Folder 26)
    - Reading Lists/Outlines, 1977 (Box 1, Folder 27)
    - Reading Lists/Outlines, 1978 (Box 1, Folder 28)
    - Reading Lists/Outlines, 1978 (Box 1, Folder 29)
    - Reading Lists/Outlines, 1979 (Box 1, Folder 30)
    - Reading Lists/Outlines, 1979 (Box 1, Folder 31)
    - Reading Lists/Outlines, 1980 (Box 1, Folder 32)
    - Reading Lists/Outlines, 1980 (Box 1, Folder 33)
    - Reading Lists/Outlines, 1981 (Box 1, Folder 34)
    - Reading Lists/Outlines, 1981 (Box 1, Folder 35)
    - Reading Lists/Outlines, 1982 (Box 1, Folder 36)
    - Reading Lists/Outlines, 1982 (Box 1, Folder 37)
    - Reading Lists/Outlines, 1983 (Box 1, Folder 38)
    - Reading Lists/Outlines, 1983 (Box 1, Folder 39)
    - Reading Lists/Outlines, 1984 (Box 1, Folder 40)
    - Reading Lists/Outlines, 1984 (Box 1, Folder 41)
    - Reading Lists/Outlines, 1985 (Box 1, Folder 42)
    - Reading Lists/Outlines, 1986 (Box 1, Folder 43)
    - Reading Lists/Outlines, 1986 (Box 1, Folder 44)
    - Reading Lists/Outlines, 1987 (Box 1, Folder 45)
    - Reading Lists/Outlines, 1987 (Box 2, Folder 46)
    - Reading Lists/Outlines, 1987 (Box 2, Folder 55)
    - Reading Lists/Outlines, 1988 (Box 2, Folder 47)
    - Reading Lists/Outlines, 1988 (Box 2, Folder 48)
    - Reading Lists/Outlines, 1989 (Box 2, Folder 49)
    - Reading Lists/Outlines, 1989 (Box 2, Folder 50)
    - Reading Lists/Outlines, 1990 (Box 2, Folder 51)
    - Reading Lists/Outlines, 1990 (Box 2, Folder 52)
    - Reading Lists/Outlines, 1991 (Box 2, Folder 53)
    - Reading Lists/Outlines, 1991 (Box 2, Folder 54)
  - B. Intro Economics Course
    - Documentation of Consumer Economics and Housing and Economics Agreement with Respect to teaching Intro Economics Courses, 1995-1997 (Box 5, Folder 9)
    - Documentation of Consumer Economics and Housing and Economics Agreement with Respect to Intro Economic Courses, 1995-1997 (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - C. Theses
    - Consumer Economics and Housing Theses Lists, 1926-1997 (Box 6, Folder 1)
    - Theses Abstracts, 1938-1990 (Box 6, Folder 2-5)
- Series III. Handbooks
  - A. Department
    - Department Handbook, 1985-1986 (Box 4)
    - Department Handbook, 1976-1977 (Box 4)
    - Department Handbook, 1975-1976 (Box 4)
    - Department Handbook, 1974-1975 (Box 4)
    - Department Handbook, 1973-1974 (Box 4)
    - Department Handbook, 1972-1973 (Box 4)
    - Department Handbook, 1971-1972 (Box 4)
    - Economic Outlook Conference Consumer Handbook, 1995-12 (Box 4)
    - Consumer Economic Outlook Handbook, 1996-1997 (Box 4)
  - B. Graduate
    - Graduate Handbook, 1997, 1998 (Box 5, Folder 17)
- Series IV. Minutes of Meetings
  - A. "The Committee" and Executive Committee
    - Minutes of "The Committee" and Executive Committee, 1989-1995 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - B. Curriculum Committee
    - Curriculum Committee Material, Committee on Adoption Policy, Retirement Committee, 1986-1997 (Box 5, Folder 7)
    - Committees-Consumer Economics and Housing, 1986-1997 (Box 5, Folder 8)
    - Committees - Assignments, 1976-1989 (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - C. Faculty Meetings
    - Department Faculty Meetings, 1993 (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Department Faculty Meetings, 1992 (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - Department Faculty Meetings, 1991 (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - Department Faculty Meetings, 1990 (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - Department Faculty Meetings, 1987-1989 (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - Department Faculty Meetings, 1980-1984 (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - Department Faculty Meetings, 1977-1979 (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - Faculty Memos, 1992-1993 (Box 1, Folder 17)
    - Faculty Meeting Minutes, 1992-03-06 (Box 5, Folder 13)
    - Faculty Meeting Minutes, 1995-03-07-1996 (Box 5, Folder 14)
    - Faculty Meeting Minutes- Joint Consumer Economics and Housing and Human Service Studies, 1996-1997 (Box 5, Folder 15)
    - Faculty Meeting Minutes-Joint Consumer Economics and Housing and Human Service Studies, 1996-1997 (Box 5, Folder 16)
  - D. Graduate Advisory Committee
    - Graduate Advisory Committee, 1985-1993 (Box 8, Folder 7)
- Series V. Publications
  - Publication Lists, 1976-1995 (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - Publication "Echo", 1986-1989 (Box 5, Folder 18)
  - Publication "Echo", 1989-1996 (Box 5, Folder 19)
  - Consumer Economics and Housing Alumni News, 1986 (Box 5, Folder 19)
  - "Consumer Close-Ups" - Topical Index (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - "Consumer Close-Ups", 1971-1974 (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - "Consumer Close-Ups", 1975-1979 (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - "Consumer Close-Ups", 1980-1982 (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - "Consumer Close-Ups", 1983-1986 (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - "Consumer Close-Ups", 1987-1989 (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - "Consumer Close-Ups", 1990-1997 (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - "Consumer Economics and Housing Topics", 1983-1988 (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - "Consumer Economics and Housing Topics", 1989-1992 (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - "Consumer Economics and Housing Topics", 1989-1996 (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - Keith Bryant's Publications on the Future of Consumer Economics, 1989-1999 (Box 7, Folder 11)
  - "Consumer Economics and Housing News", 1984 (Box 7, Folder 12)
  - Former Chairs of the Dept. of Consumer Economics and Housing -Gwen Bymers, Scott Maynes, Keith Bryant, Jean Robinson, Richard Burkhauser, 1998 (Box 7, Folder 13)
- Series VI. Reports/Plans
  - A. Annual
    - Annual Reports- Faculty, 1992-1993 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Annual Reports- Faculty, 1991-1992 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Annual Reports- Faculty, 1990-1991 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Annual Reports
      - 1968-07-01-1969-06-30 (Box 3)
      - 1969-07-01-1970-06-30 (Box 3)
      - 1970-07-01-1971-06-30 (Box 3)
      - 1971-07-01-1972-06-30 (Box 3)
      - 1972-07-01-1973-06-30 (Box 3)
      - 1973-07-01-1974-06-30 (Box 3)
      - 1974-07-01-1975-06-30 (Box 3)
      - 1975-07-01-1976-06-30 (Box 3)
      - 1976-07-01-1977-06-30 (Box 3)
      - 1977-07-01-1978-06-30 (Box 3)
      - 1978-07-01-1979-06-30 (Box 3)
      - 1979--07-01-1980-06-30 (Box 3)
      - 1980-07-01-1981-06-30 (Box 3)
      - 1981-07-01-1982-06-30 (Box 3)
      - 1982-07-01-1983-06-30 (Box 3)
      - 1983-07-01-1984-06-30 (Box 3)
      - 1984--07-01-1985-06-30 (Box 3)
      - 1985-07-01-1986-06-30 (Box 3)
      - 1986-07-01-1987-06-30 (Box 3)
      - 1987-07-01-1988-06-30 (Box 3)
      - 1988-07-01-1989-06-30 (Box 3)
      - 1989-07-01-1990-06-30 (Box 3)
      - 1990-07-01-1991-06-30 (Box 3)
      - 1991-07-01-1992-06-30 (Box 3)
      - 1992-07-01-1993-06-30 (Box 3)
      - 1993-07-01-1994-06-30 (Box 3)
    - Annual Reports-Faculty, 1994-1995 (Box 5, Folder 1)
    - Annual Reports-Faculty, 1995-1996 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - B. Five Year Plans
    - Five Year Plans (Box 1, Folder 2)
      - Special Review, 1978
      - CE & PP Master Plan, 1976-1980; 1980-1984
      - Master Plan, 1975
      - Interlocking Growth Projection, 1970-1975
      - 5 Year Plan, 1980
      - Current Research, 1980
  - C. Master Plans
    - Master Plans (Box 1, Folder 3)
      - Statement of College-Wide Goals and Priorities, 1980-1986
      - Campus Master Plan, 1980
      - College Long Range Planning Document, 1985-1988
  - D. Reviews
    - "Consumer Economics at Cornell: A Chronicle" by Gwen Bymers and material on the Household Economics and Management Reunion, 1980, 1981 (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - Department of Consumer Economics and Housing-materials prepared for external review-Jean Robinson, Chairman, 1986-03 (Box 4, Folder 2)
    - Consumer Economics and Housing- Department Review- Scott Maynes, Chairman, 1978 (Box 4, Folder 3)
    - Consumer Economics and Housing-Policies and Procedures, 1996 (Box 4, Folder 4)
    - Cooperative State Research Service Comprehensive Dept. Review, 1986-03-17-1986-03-19 (Box 1, Folder 48)
  - E. Chair's Reports to the Dean
    - Chair's Reports to the Dean, 1981-1982; 1983-1984,; 1985-1986,; 1987-1989,; 1992-1993 (Box 1, Folder 46)
  - F. Various other Reports
    - Various other Reports (Box 1, Folder 49)
      - Organized Research and Public Service Programming, 1969
      - Year-end Report, 1969-1970
      - Interlocking Growth Projection, 1970-1976
      - Consumer Economics and Housing Highlights-Faculty Developments, 1980-1981
    - Summary Of Comments On Graduate Program and Current Employment From Recipients of MS And PhD Degrees In The Management, Housing And Equipment Division, 1962-1972 (Box 2, Folder 62)
- Series VII. Subject Files
  - Faculty Advisor Lists, 1971-1990 (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - Faculty Who's Who, 1980-1997 (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - Department Christmas Party, 1988 (Box 7, Folder 14)
  - History (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Evolution of the Department
    - Mission Statement, 1993
    - Report of the Study Committee in Economics, 1969
  - Field Study-Consumer Economics and Housing (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - "Substance Abuse Among Youth in the Rockaways", 1986
    - "Essex Street Market Research Project", 1986
  - Field Study-Consumer Economics and Housing (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - "Clinton at the Crossroads"-Study of the Clinton Urban Renewal Area, 1987
    - "Extending the Caring Community"-Study of New York City Home Health Care Industry, 1988
  - "Building a Home Buyers' Educational Program"-Final Report, 1993 (Box 1, Folder 47)
  - Reorganization of Department, 1969 (Box 1, Folder 50)
  - Field Study for Consumer Economics and Housing Students, 1985-1990 (Box 2, Folder 56)
  - Summer Research Fellowships in Consumer Economics and Housing, 1987-1990 (Box 2, Folder 57)
  - Graduate Program, 1992-1994 (Box 2, Folder 58)
  - Graduate Program Consumer Economics and Housing, 1988-1992, 1995-1996 (Box 2, Folder 59)
  - Graduate Program, 1985-1988 (Box 2, Folder 60)
  - Graduate Program, Graduate Faculty Meetings, 1984-1985, 1995-1996 (Box 2, Folder 61)
- Series VII. Photographs
  - Former Chairs of the Department of Consumer Economics and Housing, 1998 (Box 7, Folder 7)
    Gwen Bymers, Scott Maynes, Keith Bryant, Jean Robinson, Richard Burkhauser